Sivakumar Dayalan

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India



linkedin.com/in/sivakumar-dayalan-115b3797



sivainspy@gmail.com



9003158266

Summary

Application Developer who worked in Big Data Environment, where its ecosystem comprises of Hadoop, Hive, Spark, Oozie, Sqoop, Solr, NiFi, MySQL and other industrial technologies like Shell Scripting, Control-M, Teradata, MongoDB, Python, Java, Selenium and JMeter.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

Tech Mahindra

May 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months +)

Associate Consultant Senior Test Engineer

Amtex Software Solutions Pvt Ltd

Jul 2017 - May 2019 (1 year 11 months)

Hadoop/Big Data Testing and Deployment in IoT



Technical Editor

Scientific Publishing Services Pvt Ltd

Nov 2014 - Jul 2017 (2 years 9 months)

Microsoft Word Tool (WEST), Manual Testing, VB Scripting, PMS, XML, HTML

XML Programmer

Deccan iServices Pvt. Ltd.

Oct 2013 - Jul 2014 (10 months)

APTARA XML Tool Testing, Error Handling, Defect Log, XML, HTML

Process Executive

Cal C Soft Pvt Ltd

Sep 2012 - Sep 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Proof Reading, PDF Creation, PDF Compare, Kindle, MS Word, Abby Fine Reader, HTML Layout

Education



S. A. Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science

2009 - 2012

B.E CSE



Murugappa Polytechnic College, Avadi

DECE, Electronics and Communication Engineering

2006 - 2009

Learned to ask questions and to troubleshoot equipment.

Licenses & Certifications

Certified Associate in Software Testing (CAST) - Talent Sprint

Honors & Awards

Performer of the Year - Chairman & CEO

Dec 2018

Got appreciation for my fine service as the outstanding performer of the year

Skills

Hadoop • Hive • Spark • Requirements Analysis • Bigdata • HTML • CSS • XML • JavaScript • SQL